A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, officers' diaries, RG 12, F-L FA392
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Grant, John B., 1.18 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes and 3 microfilm boxes (35mm)
  - 1950, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Grant, John B. (1890-1962); 258 pages (Reel M Gra 3, Frame 23, Box 175)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Grant, professionals and students in the field of public health. Grant continues to focus on social medicine and its relation to medical care. He visits various organizations and institutions associated with social medicine and discussed teaching of hospital and medical care administration, medical economics and medical care. The bulk of the diary focuses on fellowship applicants and travel grants, the venereal disease project, surveying American health and medical practices, touring Indochina and organizing a health survey in Italy. Includes a report entitled, "Gleaning from the American Vintage."
    Venereal diseases; Vietnam; Medical education; Tuberculosis; Typhoid fever; United States; Indonesia; Malaria; Medical care; Medical economics; Gonorrhea; Health insurance; Hospitals -- Administration; Hygiene; Cost and standard of living; France; Finland; Portugal; Public health; Medicine, Preventive; Penicillin; Scotland; Singapore; Public health nursing; Sanitation; Syphilis; Thailand; Diaries; Social medicine; Switzerland; World Health Organization
  - Index, 1951; Grant, John B. (1890-1962); World Health Organization; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medicine and Public Health (Box 175, Reel M Gra 3, Frame 307)
    1951 Index; 15 pages divided between interviews held in United States and Europe.
  - 1951, World Health Organization; Grant, John B. (1890-1962); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medicine and Public Health; 180 pages (Box 175, Reel M Gra 3, Frame 322)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Grant, professionals and students in the field of public health. Grant continues to focus on social medicine and its relation to medical care. He visits various organizations and institutions associated with social medicine and discussed teaching of hospital and medical care administration, medical economics and medical care. The bulk of the diary focuses on fellowship applicants and travel grants, studies of medical care planning and building up public health facilities in Europe. In 1951, Grant became associate director of RF Division of Medicine and Public Health.
    Public health; Diaries; United States; England; Finland; France; Switzerland; Sweden; Social medicine; Public health nursing; Medical economics; Medical education; Medicine, Preventive; Netherlands; Health insurance; Hospitals -- Administration; Hygiene; Medical care
  - Index, 1952; Grant, John B. (1890-1962); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medicine and Public Health (Box 175, Reel M Gra 3, Frame 527)
    1952 Index; 33 pages.
  - 1952, Grant, John B. (1890-1962); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medicine and Public Health; 187 pages (Box 175, Reel M Gra 3, Frame 560)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Grant, professionals and students in the field of public health. Grant continues to focus on social medicine and its relation to medical care. He visits various organizations and institutions associated with social medicine and discussed teaching of hospital and medical care administration, medical economics and medical care. He attends various conferences on comprehensive medical care and public health.
    Hygiene; Hospitals -- Administration; Medical economics; Medical care; Canada; Health insurance; United States; Social medicine; Diaries; Medicine, Preventive; Medical education; Public health nursing; Public health
  - Index, 1953; Grant, John B. (1890-1962); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medicine and Public Health (Box 175, Reel M Gra 3, Frame 748)
    1953 Index; 20 pages.
  - 1953, Grant, John B. (1890-1962); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medicine and Public Health; 193 pages (Reel M Gra 3, Frame 768, Box 175)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Grant, professionals and students in the field of public health. Grant continues to focus on social medicine and its relation to medical care. He visits various organizations and institutions associated with social medicine and discussed teaching of hospital and medical care administration, medical economics and medical care. He attends various conferences on comprehensive medical care and public health. He tours Taiwan and the Philippines to determine if RF support is needed. Grant also travels around the United States to survey the progress of public health programs at major American universities.
    United States; Health care financing; Health insurance; Chronic diseases; Diaries; Public health nursing; Canada; Taiwan; Social medicine; Philippines; Public health; Medical education; Medicine, Preventive; Medical care; Medical economics; Hospitals -- Administration; Hygiene
  - Index, 1954-1955; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medicine and Public Health; Grant, John B. (1890-1962) (Reel M Gra 3, Frame 961, Box 175)
    1954-1955 Index; 17 pages.
  - 1954-1955, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medicine and Public Health; Grant, John B. (1890-1962); 269 pages (Reel M Gra 3, Frame 978, Box 175)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Grant, professionals and students in the field of public health. Grant continues to focus on social medicine and its relation to medical care. He visits various organizations and institutions associated with social medicine and discussed teaching of hospital and medical care administration, medical economics and medical care. In 1954, Grant began to regionalization of medical resources of Puerto Rico. The diary also includes itinerary and visit of Rajkumari Amrit Kaur, Minister of Health of India.
    Medical care; Hygiene; Hospitals -- Administration; Health insurance; Health care financing; Chronic diseases; Social medicine; Public health nursing; Public health; Medicine, Preventive; Medical education; Medical economics; Diaries
- Grant, Ulysses J., 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  - 1953-1958 (Box 176)
  - 1959-1960 (Box 176)
  - 1960-1964 (Box 177)
  - 1965-1968 (Box 177)
- Gray, Clarence C., III, 0.57 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box and 1 half-letter box
  - 1973-1976 (Box 178)
  - 1977 (Box 178)
  - 1978 (Box 178)
  - 1979-1983 (Box 179)
- Greene, Roger Sherman, 0.19 Cubic Feet 1 half-letter document box
  Roger Greene was born in Westborough, Massachusetts, in 1881, while his missionary parents were on furlough in United States. Daniel and Mary Jane Greene had devoted their adult lives to bringing Western-style education to Japan. As a result of their work, Roger Greene and his seven siblings were brought up in Japan and developed strong ties to the Far East.
  Greene returned to Massachusetts to pursue his education at Harvard University. After receiving a graduate degree in 1902, Greene joined the U.S. Consular Service and worked for twelve years in a variety of locations that included Brazil, Japan and China. In 1914 Green left to join the Rockefeller Foundation (RF), where his brother Jerome Greene served as Secretary.
  Greene's first position with the RF was with the 1914 China Commission. This commission, which also included Harry Pratt Judson of the University of Chicago and Dr. Francis Peabody of Harvard Medical School, surveyed the medical and public health needs of China and determined the blueprint for future RF activities in the country. As a result of the China Commission's survey, the RF created the China Medical Board (CMB), which was instrumental in modernizing Chinese medical education. Based on his work with the Commission, and his own knowledge of Chinese language and culture, Greene was named Resident Director of the CMB in China in 1914, Director of the CMB in 1921, and Acting Director of Peking Union Medical College (PUMC) and Vice President of the RF in the Far East in 1927.
  While his work in China had garnered him accolades and promotions within the Foundation, his relationship with the organization soured over changes in its policies toward China. Greene also advocated against the imposition of Western Christianity in Chinese medical education, arguing that the Department of Religion at PUMC was expendable as the Foundation faced budget cuts during the Great Depression. Finding little support for these ideas among his American colleagues, Greene resigned from the CMB in 1934 and from PUMC in 1935.
  Following his resignation from the RF, Greene maintained his interest in China. He lobbied for American aid to the country following its invasion by Japan, and during World War II he served as a consultant to the State Department's Division of Cultural Relations. He also promoted the study of East Asian languages and cultures in America.
  Roger Greene died in 1947 in West Palm Beach, Florida and is buried in Westborough, Massachusetts.
  - 1927-1929 (Box 179)
- Gregg, Alan, 1.97 Cubic Feet 5 letter document boxes and 5 microfilm boxes (35mm)
  Alan Gregg served as an instrumental figure in the Rockefeller Foundation (RF), directing support for medical research and medical education throughout the 1930s and 1940s and rising to the office of the Vice President in 1951.
  Born in 1890 in Colorado Springs, Colorado, Gregg headed East to earn both an undergraduate (1911) and a medical degree (1916) from Harvard University. Following medical school, Gregg volunteered his services on the Western front in World War I, joining up with Great Britain's Royal Army Medical Corps in 1917 and remaining until his discharge in 1919.
  After the war Gregg began his career with the RF. In 1919 Gregg joined the International Health Division (IHD) and was immediately assigned to the field staff in Brazil. Gregg remained in Brazil until 1922, when he accepted the position of Associate Director of the RF's Division of Medical Education. In 1929 Gregg became the Associate Director of the Medical Sciences Division and one year later was promoted to director. Gregg left this position in 1951 and assumed the office of Vice President of the RF, a title he held until his retirement in 1956.
  In his work with the Medical Sciences Division, Gregg took a special interest in helping to build the field of psychiatry. Gregg firmly believed that the teaching of psychiatry and the funding of mental health research should be on par with the attention given any other disease of the body. Gregg supported initiatives that ensured the inclusion of psychiatry in standard medical school curricula and also directed RF funding toward individual researchers in the field.
  In addition to his work with the RF, Gregg served as an advisor to a number of government departments, including the Office of the Surgeon General of the War Department, the National Institute of Mental Health, and the psychiatric and neuropsychiatric sections of the Department of Veterans Affairs. Gregg also received the French National Order of the Legion of Honour and was named as an Honorary Fellow of the Royal Society of Medicine in Great Britain. In 1956, he received an award from the Lasker Foundation in 1956 that recognized his service in the fields of public health, medical education and research.
  Alan Gregg passed away in Big Sur, California in 1957.
  - 1922, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 49 pages (Box 180, Reel M Gre 1, Frame 1)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical education. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. This diary includes meetings on current RF medical fellows, a discussion on public health instruction in Canada and Brazil, and a meeting at New York Academy of Medicine to discuss new era in medicine revolving around the changing roles of patients, physicians and the community.
    Brazil; Canada; Medical education; Europe, Central; Osteopathic medicine; Medical sciences; Diaries; United States; Public health
  - Exhibits, 1922; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 11 pages (Box 180, Reel M Gre 1, Frame 50)
    Includes a Memorandum on publicizing and securing information on hookworm in Brazil, a Luncheon to Dr. A.E. Taylor and an AG Memorandum on interview with Dr. Alfred E. Cohen on Palestine.
    Exhibitions; Brazil; Medical sciences; Hookworm disease; Public health; Palestine; United States
  - 1923, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 93 pages (Reel M Gre 1, Frame 61, Box 180)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical education. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, development of new projects and financing current and future research. This diary includes an five year outline of an RF program to create a medical facility and train professionals in Bangkok, a general outline of the hookworm campaign in Mexico. Gregg also tours various medical schools, hospitals and laboratories the United States with the Japanese Commission. A trip to Columbia is taken to survey medical education, facilities and practice in Latin America and to ready for the yellow fever campaign in that region.
    Yellow fever; Colombia; Diaries; Hookworm disease; Japan; Medical education; Medical sciences; Mexico; Public health; United States
  - Exhibit, 1923; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 50 pages (Reel M Gre 1, Frame 154, Box 180)
    Includes: "New York Academy of Medicine Proposed Budget", "Memorandum of an Informal Conference on Policies of Russian Relief", "Memorandum from Mr. Hoover to the National Information Bureau", "Luncheon Conference Concerning Fellowships in Biology", "Program of the Thirty-third Annual Meeting of the Association of American Medical Colleges", "Report of Committee on Curriculum", "Committee of Reception for the Visiting Commission of Japanese Medical Scientists Who Are Visiting the United States Under the Auspices of the Rockefeller Foundation", "Program Dinner to Visiting Commission of Japanese Medical Scientists", "Notes on the Visit of Doctor Fujinami", "Division of Laboratories and Research New York State Department of Health", "Program of the Fifty-second annual meeting of the American Public Health Association".
    Colombia; Biology -- Research; Exhibitions; Hookworm disease; Japan; Medical education; Medical sciences; United States; Russia; Public health; Mexico; Yellow fever
  - 1924, Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; 74 pages (Reel M Gre 1, Frame 204, Box 180)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical education. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, development of new projects and financing current and future research. This diary includes a conference in Baltimore, visits to Italy and France, and an inter-office letter titled "Information on the Commission for the prevention of tuberculosis in France"
    Tuberculosis; Public health; Medical sciences; Medical education; United States; Italy; Diaries; France
  - Exhibit, 1924; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; 5 pages (Box 180, Reel M Gre 1, Frame 289)
    Progress report on French University of Montreal.
    Medical education; Exhibitions; Canada; Medical sciences
  - 1925, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 157 pages (Reel M Gre 1, Frame 294, Box 180)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical education. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Stationed at the RF Paris Office as Associate Director of Medical Education, Gregg studies present day needs in medical education, develops programs with medical schools to improve facilities. He holds preliminary studies to assess needs and establish support programs in Italy and Ireland.
    Diaries; France; Ireland; Norway; Public health; Italy; Medical education
  - Index, 1926; Gregory, John D.; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education (Box 180, Reel M Gre 1, Frame 453)
    A 26 page alphabetical index to the 1926 diary
    Europe; France; Austria; England; Medical education; Public health; indexes (reference sources); Italy
  - 1926, Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; 194 pages (Box 180, Reel M Gre 1, Frame 478)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical education. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Stationed at the RF Paris Office as Associate Director of Medical Education, Gregg studies present day needs in medical education, develops programs with medical schools to improve facilities. He visits and surveys various medical institutions and determines if they need RF assistance. Scientific literature, laboratory supplies and emergency aid programs are discussed and granted to various medical institutions.
    Diaries; Medical education; France; Public health; Austria; Europe; England
  - Index, 1927; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957) (Reel M Gre 1, Frame 672, Box 180)
    A 29 page alphabetical index to the 1927 diary
    Scotland; Soviet Union; Spain; United States; England; Croatia; Bulgaria; Austria; Iceland; indexes (reference sources); France; Hungary; Medical education; Public health; Ireland; Italy; Public health nursing
  - 1927, Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; 181 pages (Box 180, Reel M Gre 1, Frame 701)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical education. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. Stationed at the RF Paris Office as Associate Director of Medical Education, Gregg studies present day needs in medical education, develops programs with medical schools to improve facilities. He tours around Europe and the Soviet Union to survey local medical and nursing education. The University of Lyon program is discussed with emphasizes preclinical laboratory work and the construction of a new health center.
    Ireland; Iceland; Hungary; France; Public health nursing; Public health; Medical education; Italy; Diaries; United States; Spain; Soviet Union; Scotland; Austria; Bulgaria; Croatia; England
  - Index, 1928; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education (Box 180, Reel M Gre 1, Frame 882)
    A 25 page alphabetical index to the 1928 diary
    Medical education; indexes (reference sources); Holland (Netherlands: Province); Germany; France; England; Denmark; Public health; Public health nursing
  - 1928, Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; 119 pages (Reel M Gre 1, Frame 907, Box 180)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical education. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. Stationed at the RF Paris Office as Associate Director of Medical Education, Gregg studies present day needs in medical education, develops programs with medical schools to improve facilities. He tours around Europe to survey local medical and nursing education. He also works on his Russian visit report.
    Public health nursing; Medical education; Public health; Diaries; Germany; Holland (Netherlands: Province); England; France; Denmark
  - Index, 1929; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education (Box 180, Reel M Gre 2, Frame 1)
    Scope and Contetns note
    A 25 page alphabetical index to the 1929 diary
    indexes (reference sources); Medicine -- Research; Medical education; Public health; France; Scotland; Holland (Netherlands: Province); Sweden; Switzerland; England
  - 1929, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 189 pages (Reel M Gre 2, Frame 26, Box 180)
    Scope and Content note
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical education. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. Stationed at the RF Paris Office as Associate Director of Medical Education, Gregg studies present day needs in medical education, develops programs with medical schools to improve facilities. 1929 marks the beginning of a change in direction of the Medical Sciences Division. The program's emphasis will focus more on research and less on educational aid assistance. This diary includes, "Interview with Mr. Charlety, Rector of the University of Paris, May 4, 1929."
    England; France; Diaries; Holland (Netherlands: Province); Medical education; Medicine -- Research; Public health; Scotland; Sweden; Switzerland
  - Index, 1930; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957) (Box 180, Reel M Gre 2, Frame 215)
    A 25 page alphabetical index to the 1930 diary
    France; Europe; indexes (reference sources); Greece; Medicine -- Research; Medical education; Scotland; Public health; United States; England
  - 1930, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 173 pages (Box 181, Reel M Gre 2, Frame 240)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Gregg discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of medical education. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, selection of RF fellows, and development of new projects. Stationed at the RF Paris Office as Associate Director of Medical Education, Gregg studies present day needs in medical education, develops programs with medical schools to improve facilities.
    United States; Public health; Scotland; Diaries; Europe; England; Greece; France; Medicine -- Research; Medical education
  - Index, 1931; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957) (Reel M Gre 2, Frame 415, Box 181)
    A 4 page alphabetical index to the 1931 diary
    Canada; Medical education; Medicine -- Research; France; indexes (reference sources); Public health; United States; Neurosciences; Psychiatry
  - 1931, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Gregg, Alan (1890-1957); 107 pages (Box 181, Reel M Gre 2, Frame 419)